Guide to the Collection of Ephemera on the Book in California
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Collection of Ephemera on the Book in California
1807-1951
WA MSS S-2901
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
10.47
(26 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of pamphlets, broadsides, and other ephemera concerning the history of the book in California collected by John Swingle (Yale 1943), proprietor of Alta California Bookstore, Berkeley, California. Materials relate to publishing, fine presses, booksellers, collectors, and institutions in California. Items include pamphlets on California book organizations, such as the Book Club of California; catalogues of booksellers, presses, and institutions; and files on individuals involved with the book arts and trade.
Major printers, presses, institutions, organizations, libraries, and booksellers are represented with files. Hubert Howe Bancroft, H.H. Bancroft and Company, and the Bancroft Library of the University of California, Berkeley, is extensively documented, as is the work of printers Ward Ritchie, John Henry Nash, James Ladd Delkin, Clyde Browne, and Grant Edward Dahlstrom and the Flame, Garret, Grabhorn, Eucalyptus, Acorn, Castle, and Colt presses. Libraries and educational institutions, including the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery; the William Andrews Clark Memorial Library of the University of California, Los Angeles; San Francisco Public Library; Pasadena Public Library; Los Angeles Public Library; California State Library; Mills College; and the University of California system are documented through extensive files. California book clubs and historical societies are also well-represented, including the Book Club of California; the Bohemian Club; the Roxburghe Club; the California Society of Etchers; the Library Association of California; the California Historical Society; and the Historical Society of Southern California. Finally, booksellers and companies represented in the collection include Jake Zeitlin Books, Paul Elder and Company; Ernest Dawson and Dawson's Book Shop; and Swingle's Alta California Bookstore.
Further description and background information for this collection can be found in: Jennifer Pruett, "The Book in California," The Yale University Library Gazette, Vol. 54, no 1 (July 1979), pp 39-41.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Alta California Bookstore, 1975.
Small presses -- California; Private presses -- California; Printing -- California -- History; Printers -- California; Academic libraries -- California; Booksellers and bookselling -- California; Bookstores -- California; Libraries -- California; California -- Bibliography; California -- Intellectual life -- 20th Century; Pamphlets -- California -- 19th century; Pamphlets -- California -- 20th Century; Posters -- California -- 19th century; Printers -- California -- 20th Century; Swingle, John; Ritchie, Ward, 1905-1996; Nash, John Henry, 1871-1947; Huntington, Henry Edwards, 1850-1927; Cowan, Robert Ernest, 1862-1942; Bancroft, Hubert Howe, 1832-1918; Dahlstrom, Grant Edward, 1902-1980; Dawson, Ernest, 1881-1947; Delkin, James Ladd; Browne, Clyde, 1872-1942; Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery -- Catalogs; Bancroft Library; William Andrews Clark Memorial Library; Flame Press (Pasadena, Calif.); Garret Press; Grabhorn Press; Eucalyptus Press; Acorn Press; Castle Press; Colt Press -- Catalogs; Paul Elder and Company; H.H. Bancroft and Company; Book Club of California; Bohemian Club (San Francisco, Calif.); Roxburghe Club of San Francisco; California Historical Society; Mills College; University of California (1868-1952); California Society of Etchers; Library Association of California; San Francisco Public Library; Pasadena Public Library; Historical Society of Southern California; California State Library; Los Angeles Public Library; Jake Zeitlin Books (Firm: Los Angeles, Calif.); Dawson's Book Shop; Alta California Bookstore; Golden Gate International Exposition ( 1939-1940 San Francisco, Calif.)
- List of items in the Collection of Ephemera on the Book in California, undated (Box 1)
- Hughes, Elizabeth. The California of the Padres; Or, Footprints of Ancient Communism; published by I. N. Choynski, 1875 (Box 1)
- Material printed by Harry Ward Ritchie at the Flame Press, 1930; 2 (Box 1)
- The Old Garret Press publications, undated; 5 (Box 1)
- Bookplates from booksellers including Bohemian Club and Grabhorn, undated (Box 1)
- The Grabhorn Press publications, undated (Box 1)
- The History of California in Block Print by High Nine Class in Drawing, Roosevelt Jr. High School; printed by school's print shop, undated (Box 1)
- Buntline, Ned. Buffalo Bill and His Adventures in the West; published by P. O. Vickery, undated (Box 1)
- Blackstone, William. Commentaries on the Laws of England; published by Thomas B. Wait, 1807 (Box 2)
- Turner, J. A. The Cotton Planter's Manual; published by C. M. Saxton and Co., 1857 (Box 2)
- Price, W. E. Paper Covered Books: a Catalogue; published by the Book and News-Dealer, 1894 (Box 2)
- Kidd, Benjamin. Social Evolution; Charles H. Serpel (The Holmes Book Co.), 1895 (Box 3)
- Sand, George. La Mare au diable; William R. Jenkins, 1886 (Box 3)
- Coulter, Edith Margaret. "California Copyrights, 1851-1856", undated (Box 3)
- Furnishings and Equipment, Residence of John C. Augsbury 3799 Washington St. SF, 1942 (Box 3)
- Publication of Anderson & Ritchie; The Ward Ritchie Press, 1932 (Box 3)
- The Book Club of California publications, 1940 December; 3 (Box 3)
- The Grabhorn Press publications, undated; 6 (Box 3)
- Powell, Lawrence Clark. San Joaquin Vision; reprinted from the California Library Bulletin, June 1948, undated (Box 3)
- Newbegin's Bookshop list of the Allen Knight Collection, undated (Box 3)
- Carew, Harold D. "Arbiter Elegantarium," article on Robert Ernest Cowan, 1930 January (Box 3)
- Wilson, Katherine. "Something For Beauty Here," article on John Henry Nash, 1930 October (Box 3)
- Correspondence between Robin Lampson and George Fields as well as between Catherine Phillips and "Mr. Dressler", 1932-1936 (Box 3)
- Mayhew, Joyce. "Commemoration Poem"; printed by The Eucalyptus Press, 1937 (Box 3)
- The Westgate Signed Editions, undated (Box 3)
- Schad, Robert O. Beauty in Books; Esto Publishing Company, 1935 (Box 3)
- Wagner, Henry R. Commercial Printers of San Francisco from 1851 to 1880, 1939 (Box 3)
- Pioneers in Paper: the Story of Blake, Moffit & Towne, 1930 (Box 3)
- Bentley, Wilder. Excursion on the Bay; Acorn Press, 1934 February 24 (Box 4)
- Schad, Robert O. Henry Edwards Huntington, 1931 (Box 4)
- Marks of Printers Today; Pacific Printer and Publisher, 1937 (Box 4)
- The Grabhorn Press publications, undated; 3 (Box 4)
- "Collecting for Profit", 1932 January (Box 4)
- Arthur MacDonald Ellis, 1873-1932, undated (Box 4)
- Catalog of First Editions of Lafcadio Hearn; Penguin Book Shop, 1933 October (Box 4)
- Telegram from Catherine Phillips to Albert Dressler, undated (Box 4)
- Catalogue of Auction Sale of the Library Etchings and Prints of the Late Fisher Ames, undated (Box 4)
- The Fine Art of Reveiling; imprinted by The Auk Press, 1936 (Box 4)
- Simpson, George. Narrative of a Voyage to California Ports in 1841-42; a Russell Private Press Volume, undated (Box 4)
- "Books in the Hitchcock Library", undated (Box 4)
- Hoffmansthal, Hugo von. Everyman; The Primavera Press, 1936 (Box 4)
- Jake Zeitlin Books advertisement, undated (Box 4)
- "Huntington Library Duplicates, List No. 3", undated (Box 4)
- Seventy-Five Years of History of the Mechanics' Institute of San Francisco, 1930 (Box 4)
- Quarterly News-Letter of the Book Club of California, 1936-1938; 2 (Box 4)
- Travel Trails; edited by W. L. Brosch, The C. T. & T. Bureau, 1932 (Box 4)
- Cowan, Robert Ernest & Cowan, Robert Granniss. A Bibliography of the History of California, 1510-1930; printed by John Henry Nash, 1932 (Box 4)
- Auction Sale: list from the Lure of California Catalogue; Butterfield Studios, 1931 (Box 4)
- Wheat, Carl I. Pioneers; privately printed, 1934 (Box 4)
- Announcements by the Roxburghe Club of San Francisco, 1935; 3 (Box 4)
- Some Preliminary Ideas for the Complete Penn-Mead Tryal; edited by Edwin Grabhorn, undated (Box 4)
- Pamphlets from the California College of Arts and Crafts, Oakland, 1936 (Box 4)
- History and Description of Paper Making; published by the Zellerbach Paper Company, 1937 (Box 4)
- Gelber, Lilienthal, Inc. Catalogue of First Editions, 1928 (Box 4)
- Christmas card facsimile printed by John Henry Nash and his wife, Mary Henrietta, 1924 (Box 4)
- Thomas C. Russell publications, 1920, undated (Box 4)
- Literature of the West: Duplicates from the Library of Henry E. Huntington, 1923 (Box 5)
- The Works of Charles F. Lummis, 1928; 2 (Box 5)
- Jake Zeitlin Books publications, 1924-1931, undated; 5 (Box 5)
- Older, Fremont. My Own Story; The Post-Enquirer Publishing Co., 1925 (Box 5)
- Material printed by John Henry Nash, 1925-1929; 2 (Box 5)
- California Number of Troubador, Vol. 1, no.8, 1929 May (Box 5)
- California Bibliographies; California Historical Society, 1924 (Box 5)
- Americana; American Art Association, Inc., undated (Box 5)
- Stevenson, Robert Louis. A Lodging for the Night; Windsor Press, 1926 (Box 5)
- The Book Club of California: Its Purposes, Membership and List of Publications, 1928 (Box 5)
- Cowan, Robert Ernest. Norton I, Emperor of the United States and Protector of Mexico; California Historical Society, 1923 (Box 5)
- Dickens, Charles. Castles; Haywood H. Hunt, printer, 1921 (Box 5)
- Schott, Walter Edgar. The Immaculate Deception; printed by the author, undated (Box 6)
- Auction Sale, The Romance of California Catalogue; Curtis Studio, 1924 June (Box 6)
- Dawson's Book Shop catalogues, 1928-1948; 3 (Box 6)
- Letters and Press Comments; The Hall Publishing Company, undated (Box 6)
- Catalogue of John Howell Books, undated (Box 6)
- Exhibition announcement printed by John Henry Nash, undated (Box 6)
- The Roxeburghe Club of San Francisco, correspondence and announcements, 1940-1945, undated (Box 6)
- James Ladd Delkin, publication announcement, undated (Box 6)
- The Caveat Book shop catalogue, 1946 April 1 (Box 6)
- William Andrews Clark Memorial Library, 1946 (Box 6)
- Horn's, the Magazine for Booklovers, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
- Book Hunters Catalogue of The Holmes Book Co., 1941 (Box 6)
- Mackenzie & Harris, Inc. Type Specimens & Price List, 1948 July 1 (Box 6)
- Quinn, Russell. History of the San Francisco - Oakland Newspaper Guild, undated (Box 7)
- The Christmas Party Quarterly from the Huntington Library, 1936-1945 (Box 7)
- The Founding of the Roxburghe Club of San Francisco, undated (Box 7)
- James Ladd Delkin publication announcements, undated; 2 (Box 7)
- Carpenter, Edwin H., Jr. Some Libraries We Have not Visited, 1947 (Box 7)
- An Evening With William Morris' Albion Proof Press, 1940 April 1 (Box 7)
- Dummy sheet for program of 1948 meeting of the Limited Editions Group, Lee Stopple, undated (Box 7)
- Dawson, Ernest. A Visit With Dr. R; privately printed, 1948 (Box 7)
- Catalogues printed by John Henry Nash, 1935-1936; 2 (Box 7)
- "Caveat"; broadside printed by Robert E. Cowan, undated (Box 7)
- Grabhorn Press publications, 1934-1939; 2 (Box 7)
- Howell, John. Important Printing Dates, 1931 (Box 7)
- Fernald, Chester Bailey. The Cat and the Cherub; printed for Albert M. Bender by Wilder & Ellen Bentley, 1938 (Box 7)
- Letter from Stewart Edward White to Mr. Newbegin, 1937 September 15 (Box 7)
- Harding, George L. A Census of California Spanish Imprints, 1833-1845, 1933 June (Box 7)
- Newspaper article on John Henry Nash, 1931 May (Box 7)
- Paul Elder and Company. Rare Books and Manuscripts, 1932 Spring (Box 7)
- Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery. Fine Books, 1936 (Box 7)
- George Fields, bookseller catalogue, undated (Box 7)
- Henry E. Huntington Library duplicate lists, 1937-1938 (Box 8)
- Domestic Trade Department. San Francisco Manufacturers of Paper Products and Printing, 1935 July (Box 8)
- Announcement printed by John Henry Nash, 1934 (Box 8)
- The Record Book of the Rancho Santa Ana Del Chino; transcribed and edited by Lindley Bynum; printed by the Vocational Printing Classes of John C. Fremont High School, 1935 June (Box 8)
- Louis Epstein's Bookshop, 1931 July (Box 8)
- Colt Press First Anniversary, 1939 (Box 8)
- Jake Zeitlin Books catalogues, 1932 July; 3 (Box 8)
- The Templeton Crocker Collection of Seventy Books from the Famous Aldine Press (1494-1595); printed by John Henry Nash, 1935 (Box 8)
- Cowan, Robert Ernest. The Spanish Press of California, 1833-1845, undated (Box 8)
- Bentley, Wilder. The Printer to the Poet; Archetype Press Chapbooks, 1937 (Box 8)
- Club Printing House Craftsmen. The Pi-Box, 1933 May (Box 8)
- Prophecy For a New Year; Eucalyptus Press, 1939 (Box 8)
- Fine Bookbindings Exhibited at the Golden Gate International Exposition; privately printed, 1939 (Box 8)
- The Abalone Song Printed For the Friends of George Sterling; Albert M. Bender, 1937 (Box 8)
- Bliss, Leslie E. "Bibliophily and Conservation of Resources in American Libraries", 1932 (Box 8)
- Thompson, Vance. The Two Deaths of Oscar Wilde / The Leaflet, Number Two, 1930 November (Box 8)
- Mills College announcement, 1935 (Box 8)
- Albert Bender's Birthday, 1938 (Box 8)
- Parish, John C. California Books and Manuscripts in the Huntington Library, 1935 April (Box 8)
- Noah; card printed by the Grabhorn Press for Albert Bender, 1938 (Box 8)
- Cowan, Robert Ernest. Alexander S. Taylor, 1817-1876: First Bibliographer of California, 1933 March (Box 8)
- The Book Club of California, Christmas sale list, 1935 (Box 8)
- Gelber, Lilienthal, Inc. Catalogue of First Editions of American Authors, 1930 June (Box 8)
- In Which; published by Norman Bel Geddes, 1916 (Box 8)
- George Fields catalogue, undated (Box 8)
- Photograph of the Bohemian Grove, undated (Box 9)
- Card from the People's Library and Book Omnorium, undated (Box 9)
- Announcement of book sale by John Howell, 1912 October (Box 9)
- Sunset Magazine, 1906 May (Box 9)
- The Book Club of California material, 1913-1917, undated; 8 (Box 9)
- The Jitney News in manila envelope addressed to Robert Cowan, 1916 (Box 9)
- Paul Elder & Company booklist, undated (Box 9)
- California Society of Etchers exhibition announcement, 1914 (Box 9)
- San Francisco Public Library Monthly Bulletin, 1916 December (Box 9)
- Historical Society of Southern California. Annual Publications, 1915-1916 (Box 9)
- California State Library. California Newspapers in State Library, 1911 (Box 9)
- A Letter from Harrison Gray Otis, 1917 (Box 9)
- Older, Fremont. Why I Left the Bulletin and Have Come to the Call, undated (Box 9)
- Check-List or Brief Catalogue of the Library of Henry E. Huntington, 1919 (Box 9)
- Irwin, Wallace. A Tragedy in Printer's Ink; Taylor, Nash & Taylor, 1913 (Box 9)
- The Little Review, 1916 June-July (Box 9)
- Card from Jones' Book Store, undated (Box 9)
- Working card of Clark Alberti, member of the San Diego Typographical Union, 1918 (Box 9)
- Bookplate of Robert E. Cowan, undated (Box 9)
- Open house announcement for John Howell bookshop, 1925 March (Box 9)
- Temple Fine Arts. A Catalog of Helpful Books and Cards, undated (Box 9)
- Curtis Studio. Catalogue of a Valuable Library, 1914 October (Box 9)
- California State Library. News Notes of California Libraries, 1917 (Box 9)
- Notice to subscribers regarding carriers from the San Francisco Chronicle Publishing Company, 1915 August 24 (Box 10)
- Whitaker & Ray Co. "Wholesale and Retail Price List", 1904 (Box 10)
- Cowan, Robert E. The Spanish Press of California, 1833-1844, undated (Box 10)
- Announcement for Socialist Party Campaign picnic, 1911 September (Box 10)
- Arroyo Craftsman; Arroyo Guild, 1909 October (Box 10)
- Los Angeles Public Library. California in Print, undated (Box 10)
- Sophocles. The Antigone; Paul Elder and Morgan Shepard, 1902 (Box 10)
- Paul Elder & Company catalogue, 1907 (Box 10)
- Card from Catholic Art and Book Co., San Francisco, undated (Box 10)
- Pacific Science Press pamphlet, undated (Box 10)
- "Father Engelhardt's Historical Works", undated (Box 10)
- Souvenir Album of Adventism; published by Messiah's Advocate, 1902 January (Box 10)
- Argonaut Publishing Company. Argonaut Stories, undated (Box 10)
- James, George Wharton. Fremont in California, 1903 (Box 10)
- Philopolis, 1907 September 25 (Box 10)
- West Coast Magazine, 1907 September (Box 10)
- Two business cards of Robert E. Cowan, undated (Box 10)
- Pamphlets and reviews on Daniel T. Ames, undated (Box 10)
- Library Association of California. California Library Laws, 1850-1903 (Box 10)
- The Tatler of Society in California, 1907 October (Box 10)
- Tentative Plan Proposed for a New Library Building for the University of California; Berkeley, The University Press, 1901 September (Box 10)
- University of California Bulletins, 1906 April (Box 10)
- "The Bookbinding Problem Solved", undated (Box 10)
- Flugel, Edward. Henry Bradshaw; Library Association of California, 1904 (Box 10)
- Impressions; published by D. P. Elder & Morgan Shephard, 1901 October (Box 10)
- Newspaper article in the San Francisco Chronicle on the death of William Butterfield, 1908 August (Box 10)
- Newspaper articles in the San Francisco Examiner on the sale of the Mercantile Library colleciton, 1903 August; 2 (Box 10)
- Capital Book Store booklist, undated (Box 10)
- Stanley-Taylor Company advertisement, undated (Box 10)
- California Historic-Genealogical Society. Publication No. III, 1902 (Box 10)
- Paul Elder and Morgan Shepard (Firm), catalogues, 1901-1902; 3 (Box 11)
- Paul Elder and Company, catalogues, 1904-1906, undated; 3 (Box 11)
- Subscription order form from the Mirror Publishing Company, undated (Box 11)
- Envelope from Harris and Jones, blank book manufacturers, undated (Box 11)
- California Equal Suffrage Association. "List For Librarians: Votes for Women Books", undated (Box 11)
- Cunningham, Curtiss & Welch, title and author list, undated (Box 11)
- Redlands - California, pamphlet issued by the Board of Trade, undated (Box 11)
- San Francisco Chronicle, Vol. LVII, No. 98 - Vol. LVIII, No. 169, 1893 (Box 11)
- The California System of Vertical Writing; H. S. Crocker Company, 1896 (Box 11)
- Los Angeles Public Library Bulletin, Vol. I, No. 6-11, Vol. III, No. 12, 1892-1897; 2 (Box 11)
- Catalogue of the Practitioners' Series; Bancroft-Whitney Co., 1891 (Box 11)
- The American Art Printer, Vol. VI, No. 1, 1892 August (Box 11)
- Carbon of letter from W. C. Conroy, Sheriff of Place County ordering arrest of H. L. Parker for embezzlement, 1891 April 20 (Box 11)
- Transactions of the San Francisco Microscopical Society, 1893 (Box 11)
- Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam, translated by Edward Fitzgerald; The Dodge Book and Stationery Co., Publishers, 1896 (Box 11)
- Photograph of Mrs. Langtry, 1882 (Box 11)
- Correspondence between The San Francisco News Company and T. H. Griffin, 1891, undated (Box 11)
- Bookplate of M. H. de Young, undated (Box 11)
- "Librarian's Report for the Public School in Rich Bar Districts, Plumas County", 1893-1894 (Box 11)
- The Epilark, No. 25, 1897 May (Box 11)
- "Les Jeunes," broadside with silhouettes and signatures including those of Frank Gelett Burgess and Willis Polk, 1896 (Box 11)
- Hanks, Henry G. "A California Book Worm," read at a meeting of the San Francisco Microscopical Society, 1897 June 16 (Box 11)
- Taylor, Alexander S. Bibliografa California, 1510-1863, sample sheets, 1891 (Box 12)
- Phyllida: or, the Milkmaid, No. 1, 1897 January 1 (Box 12)
- The San Francisco Women's Literary Exhibit. A List of Books by California Writers, 1893 (Box 12)
- "To the Members of the California Academy of Sciences", undated (Box 12)
- Annual reports of the Mercantile Library Association, 1891-1893 (Box 12)
- Check from the Nevada Bank, San Francisco, signed by Adolph Sutro to Hicks-Judd Co., 1897 (Box 12)
- Blank order form from P. J. Healy, undated (Box 12)
- Gayley, C. M. and Scott, F. N. A Guide to the Literature of Aesthetics; University of California Library Bulletin, no. 11, 1890 (Box 12)
- The Lark, No. 1, 9, 10, 12, 14, 15, 20, 1895-1899 (Box 12)
- Photograph of H. H. Moore bookstore, 1886 (Box 12)
- Rules and Regulations of the Board of Education and Graded Course of Study for the Public Schools of Lake County, California, 1891, July (Box 12)
- Le Petit Journal des Refusées, No. 16, 1896 Summer (Box 12)
- Edward S. Spear & Co., auction catalogues, 1892-1897; 3 (Box 12)
- Annual Report of the Board of Directors of the Los Angeles Public Library and Report of Librarian, 1890 (Box 12)
- Catalogue of the Private Library of Anson Parsons Hotaling, 1897 (Box 12)
- Bill for the Evening Post and newspaper clipping, 1891, undated (Box 12)
- Press notices for "Across the Isthmus to California in 52'" by Sarah Merriam Brooks, undated (Box 12)
- Letter from H. H. Evans, undated (Box 12)
- Adolph Sutro's Letter to the Regents of the University of California and to the Committee of Affiliated Colleges on the Selection of a Site for the Affiliated Colleges, 1895 September 5 (Box 12)
- Monthly Bulletin of the Pasadena Public Library, 1899 April (Box 12)
- Surveyor-General, Letter, With Inclosures of W. S. Green; Sun Publishing Company, 1893 (Box 12)
- Invitation to visit Sutro Library and business card of Robert F. Cowan, 1985 (Box 12)
- Sutherland, H. V. The Legend of Love; privately printed, 1893 (Box 12)
- Manning, Agnes M. Because It Was a Woman's; P. J. Thomas, Printer, undated (Box 12)
- The Arena, Vol. 2, No. 3, 1890 August (Box 13)
- Announcement of the publication of a Tourists' Guide by H. S. Crocker and Co., 1882 December (Box 13)
- Democratic State Central Committee. "Some Pertinent Facts About the State Printing Office and the Republican Candidate for State Printer"; Phillips & Smyth Print, undated (Box 13)
- The Californian Illustrated Magazine. "Summary of Contents", 1892 December (Box 13)
- Photograph by Runnels & Stateler, undated (Box 13)
- Advertisement of A Tale of Two Oceans by E. I. Barra, undated (Box 13)
- The Overland Monthly, Vol. XII, No. 70, 1888 October (Box 13)
- Barra, E. I. Tale of Two Oceans; Press of Eastman & Co., 1893 (Box 13)
- Catalogue of the Library of Joseph W. Winans; H. S. Crocker & Co., Printers, 1887 (Box 13)
- The Associated Pioneers of the Territorial Days of California. Articles of Association, Roll of Members and Catalogue of Books in the Library; Press of J. J. Caulon, 1884 (Box 13)
- Ladies of the Auburn Library Association. The Little Gem Cook Book, 1888 (Box 13)
- The Alta California Almanac and Book of Facts, 1880-1882 (Box 13)
- Library card of George Catter for the Sacramento Free Library, 1881 (Box 13)
- Special Sale of Books Comprising the Library of John W. Dwinelle, Esq., 1877 (Box 13)
- Auction catalogues by Edward S. Spear & Co., 1884-1887; 2 (Box 13)
- Printing: A Journal of the Graphic Arts, Vol. I, No. 1, 1889 September (Box 13)
- Annual reports of the Mercantile Library Association, 1886-1889 (Box 14)
- San Francisco News Letter, 1887 June 18 (Box 14)
- Letter from F. Percy to J. B. Golly, undated (Box 14)
- Bookmark of the Mercantile Library, undated (Box 14)
- Auction catalogues of Edward S. Spear & Co., 1885-1887; 2 (Box 14)
- A Memento: Charles de Young, Founder of the San Francisco Chronicle, undated (Box 14)
- Addresses at the Inauguration of W. T. Reid, President of the University of California, and the Dedication of the Bacon Art and Library Building, Berkeley, August 23, 1881 (Box 14)
- Signature of California State Librarian and seal, 1882 August 28 (Box 14)
- Reviews of "Sixty Years in California", undated (Box 14)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes bookplate of Robert Ernest Cowan.
- Bill from Kusel and Son, Books and Stationery, circa 1884 (Box 14)